Register of the Khristianskii Soiuz Molodykh Liudei v Kharbine Miscellany
Hoover Institution Archives
Khristianskii soiuz molodykh liudei v Kharbine miscellany,
1932-1999
2001C40
Khristianskii soiuz molodykh liudei v Kharbine
6 microfilm reels (0.9 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Annual publications, pamphlets, writings, letters, lists, clippings, and photographs, relating to Young Men's Christian Associations educational activities within the Russian community in Harbin, and to alumni activities elsewhere in emigration.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Administrative History
Young Men's Christian associations school in Harbin, China.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains documents, printed matter and photographs related to the Khristianskii Soiuz Molodykh Liudei v Kharbine (Harbin Y.M.C.A.) School and College, as well as Soiuz okonchivshikh uchebnye zavedeniia Kharbinskogo Kh.S.M.L.(Harbin Y.M.C.A. Alumni Association) in Australia and the United States.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Russians--China.; Harbin (China); Young Men's Christian associations.; Education--China.; Education.; Russia.; China.
Container List
- General File, 1932-1999. (Box 1)
  Clippings, correspondence, list of graduates and alumni association members, and writings, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Clippings, 1965-1988 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Correspondence, 1978-1982 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Lists
    - Graduates, 1932 (Folder 1: 3)
    - Members of the Harbin Y.M.C.A. Schools Alumni Association (Folder 1: 4)
  - Subject file - Harbin, China (Folder 1: 5)
  - Writings
    - Untitled holograph by Georgii Eliseev, n.d. (Folder 1: 6)
    - "Prazdnovanie 50-letiia 5-go vypuska gimnazii Kh.S.M.L.," n.d. (Folder 1: 7)
      Holograph
    - "13-yi vypusk gimnazii Kh.S.M.L. mnogo let spustia," 1997. (Folder 1: 8)
  - Miscellany (Folder 1: 9)
- Printed Matter, 1933-1996. (Box 1-4)
  Brochures and periodicals, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Brochures
    - K biologii viazovogo listoeda Ambrostoma Quadrimpressa Motsch (Coleoptera, Chrysomelidae), by A. I. Aleksandrov, 1945 (Folder 1: 10)
    - K izucheniiu razvitiia poloza uzorchatogo - Elaphe Dione Pallas, by L. M. Iakovlev, 1945 (Folder 1: 11)
    - Programma organizatsii prosvetitel'noi deiatel'nosti Kh.S.M.L. sredi russkogo naseleniia, n.d. (Folder 1: 12)
    - Promyshlennoe razvedenie piatnistyh olenei v Man'chzhurii, by M. A. Firsov, 1945 (Folder 1: 13)
    - Otchet o deiatel'nosti kluba estestvoznaniia i geografii Kh.S.M.L. za period s 1933 po 1940 gg., 1941 (Folder 1: 14)
    - Sbornik nauchnyh rabot przheval'tsev, 1942 (Folder 1: 15)
    - Spisok pervoi kollektsii mkhov iz Severnoi Man'chzhurii, 1934 (Folder 1: 16)
    - The Club of Natural Sciences and Geography and its activity (1929-1932), 1934 (Folder 1: 17)
  - Periodicals (Box 2)
    - The Annual of the Club of Natural Science and Geography of the Y.M.C.A., 1933-1934 (Folder 2: 1)
    - Biulleten' "50 letnii iubilei", Soiuz okonchivshikh gimnaziiu/institut Kh.S.M.L., 1984-1996 (Folder 2: 2-3)
    - Farewell, Y.M.C.A. College Harbin, 1933-1935 (Folder 2: 4)
    - Izvestiia kluba estestvoznaniia i geografii Kh.S.M.L., 1941 (Folder 2: 5)
    - Izvestiia kluba estestvoznaniia i geografii Kh.S.M.L. Zoologiia, 1945 (Folder 2: 6)
    - Listovka "Druz'iam ot druzei", Soiuz okonchivshikh uchebnye zavedeniia Kharbinskogo Kh.S.M.L., 1975-1999. (Folder 2: 7-8)
      Printed copy. Includes jubilee issue, 1925-1965, and appeal to the supporters of the bulletin
    - Listovka "Druz'iam ot druzei" (Box 3)
    - Listovka "Druz'iam ot druzei" (Folder 4: 1-2)
    - Zapiski Kharbinskogo obshchestva estestvoispytatelei i etnografov, #8, Arkheologiia, 1950 (Folder 4: 3)
    - Zapiski Kharbinskogo obshchestva estestvoispytatelei i etnografov, #11, T. P. Gordeev, "Liany Man'chzhurii i Primor'ia," 1954 (Folder 4: 4)
- Photographs, 1933-1935 and undated. (Folder 4: 5)
  Four prints depicting students and teachers of the Kh.S.M.L. v Kharbine School